National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor Pamphlets and Leaflets 5966
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor Pamphlets and Leaflets
1904- 1944
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor
5966
0.33 cubic feet
0.3 linear ft.
Pamplets, leaflets.
5743726
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, April 06, 2009
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 10, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5001 PAM: American Association for Labor Legislation Pamphlet File
Convict labor; National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor (U.S.); National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor (U.S.) --Archives.
5743726
- National Committee on Prison Labor Pamphlets, 1911-1913 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Prison Labor on Public Roads, 1913; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Author: Thomas J. Tynan
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets, no.14
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
  - Item 2: The National Committee on Prison Labor: Its Origin and Purpose, 1911; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: E. Stagg Whitin
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets, no.1. Reprinted from the Survey, February 18, 1911
  - Item 3: Prison Labor in the Governors' Messages, 1911; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: National Committee on Prison Labor
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets, no.3
  - Item 4: Prison Labor in the Party Platforms of 1910, 1911; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets, no.4
  - Item 5: Trade Unions and Prison Labor, 1913; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets, no. 6. Reprinted from Case and Comment, September, 1912
  - Item 6: Prison Labor in the Governors' Messages, 1912-1913, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets,no. 8
  - Item 7: The New Penology, 1913; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Theodore Roosevelt
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets, no. 9.
  - Item 8: Women and Prison Labor, 1913; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Helen Varick Boswell
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets, no. 10
  - Item 9: The Wage-Earner and the Prison Worker, 1913; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: John Mitchell
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets, no. 11
  - Item 10: Prison Labor and Prisoners' Families, 1913; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Jane Addams
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets, no. 12. Reprinted from The Ladies' Home Journal, April, 1913
  - Item 11: Why I Could Not Pardon the Contract System, 1913; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: George W. Donaghey
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets, no. 13. Reprinted from the Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, Philadelphia, March, 1913.
  - Item 12: The Reform of the Individual, 1913; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Frank Moore
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets, no. 15. Reprinted from the Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, Philadelphia, March, 1913
  - Item 13: Prison Labor and Social Justice, 1913; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: F. Emory Lyon
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets, no. 18. Reprinted from the Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, Philadelphia, March, 1913
  - Item 14: Prison Labor Reform in New Jersey, 1913; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: C. L. Stonaker
    Notes: Prison Labor Leaflets, no. 19. Reprinted from the Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, Philadelphia, March, 1913
- National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor and Other Pamphlets, 1904-1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Prisoners as Prison Reformers, 1916; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: National Committee on Prisons
    Notes: Prison Leaflets, no.33 (1916:Apr.)
  - Item 2: Testimonial Meeting in recognition of the work of Thomas Mott Osborne as Warden of Sing Sing Prison, 1916; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Isaac N. Seligman; Adolph Lewisohn; Lillian D. Wald; Felix Adler; Hugh Frayne; William H. Wadhams; Francis Lynde Stetson
    Notes: Prison Leaflets, no.34 (1916)
  - Item 3: Honor Men and Good Roads Everywhere, 1915; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: E. Stagg Whitin; Charles Henry Davis
  - Item 4: Prison Labor: Where Are We? Whither Are We Going?, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Thomas R. Slicer
    Notes: 39th National Conference of Charities and Correction
  - Item 5: Programme of Questions for the Seventh International Prison Congress to be held at Budapest, Hungary, 1905, 1904; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Samuel J. Barrows
  - Item 6: Prison Reform, 1915; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Thomas Mott Osborne
    Notes: Address delivered to the Mens Club, Bridgeport, Connecticut, February 28, 1915.
  - Item 7: Prison Bulletin, 1915; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: National Committee on Prisons and Prison Labor
    Notes: v.1:no.7 (1915:Aug.)
  - Item 8: Demonstrating Our Profession, 1915; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: William Pierson Merrill
    Notes: Bulletins Issued by the Committee on Humane Education, v.1:no.1 (1915:Aprl)
  - Item 9: French law allows the punishment of an accomplice..., Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: A. Berlet
    Notes: First Section. Third Question
  - Item 10: Juvenile Idleness and Vagabondage, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Emma de Dessewffy
    Notes: Fourth Section. Third Question.
  - Item 11: The Indeterminate Sentence, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Gustave Beck
    Notes: First Section. First Question.
  - Item 12: A Summary Report of the Industrial Relations Laboratory. Part 1: Performance of Negro Workers in Three Hundred War Plants, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Industrial Relations Laboratory
  - Item 13: What of the Prisons? A Visit to Sing Sing: Shall We Help Warden Osborne in His Revolutionary Plans?, 1915; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Harriet Bishop Waters
    Notes: Prison Leaflets, no.1 (1915)